(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-14T21:25:04.830059",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
本日は風真いろは2周年ライブにお越しいただきまして誠にありがとうございます。
Thank you very much for attending Kazama Iroha's 2nd Anniversary Live today.
本公演をご覧になるにあたっての注意事項を説明いたします。
I will now explain the viewing guidelines for this performance.
その一、全力で楽しみ。
Rule 1: Enjoy it with all your might.
その二、全力でコメントをし。
Rule 2: Comment with all your might.
その三、全力でスクショを撮り。
Rule 3: Take screenshots with all your might.
その四、全力でハッシュタグ風真いろは2周年ライブでつぶやき。
Rule 4: Tweet using #KazamaIroha2ndAnniversaryLive.
その五、全力で幸せな気持ちになっていってください。
Rule 5: Leave with a fully happy heart.
それではまもなく開演いたします。
The performance will begin shortly.
風真いろはは、どこへでもいける！
Kazama Iroha can go anywhere!
きらきら、光ってるはずなんだ
Sparkling, we're bound to shine bright
キャパシティオーバー
Capacity over!
てんてこまいの毎日だ
It's a frantic everyday life
頭こんがらがって warning warning
My head gets all tangled, warning!
でっかい月の上にウサギがいるんだっけ？
Is there a rabbit on the big moon?
宇宙旅行にパスポートって要りますか
Do you need a passport for a space trip?
僕らが歩いていくセカイの明日はどんな色？
What color is tomorrow in the world we walk?
君と僕で描いていくふたりいろ
Painted in the two colors of you and me
i shall checkmate 君を checkmate
I shall checkmate, I'm gonna checkmate you
会いたい時には会いに行くよ
I'll go see you whenever I want to
地球の裏から夢の中まで
From the other side of earth to inside dreams
ひらひら、スカートが揺れる
Fluttering, our skirts sway in harmony
escort 君を escort
Escort, I'll escort you
マニュアル通りじゃつまらないでしょ？
Following the manual isn't fun, right?
不安の数だけ希望があるってこと
That there is hope equal to our worries
きらきら、光ってるはずなんだ
Sparkling, we're bound to shine bright
エマージェンシーじゃん
It's an emergency!
なんでもありのアイドルだ
An idol who can do anything
常識もグラついちゃうって panic panic
Common sense wobbles, panic, panic!
深海、海の底でマーメイドが恋をしたって？
Did a mermaid fall in love at the bottom of the sea?
嘘か本当か確かめにいきませんか
Shall we go check if it's true or false?
僕らの暮らしてるセカイは人ひとりひとりの色
The world we live in is made of unique colors
それはお父さんお母さんのあいだのいろ
The colors born from our parents' love
i shall checkmate 君を checkmate
I shall checkmate, I'm gonna checkmate you
雨降り天気でも会いに行くよ
I'll go see you even in the pouring rain
果報が来るまで寝とけばいいってマジ？
Is it true I can just sleep until good news arrives?
いやいや、待てるわけなくね
No way, there's no way I can wait!
絶好調、もうずっと絶好調
Perfect, always staying at my best
片道切符で構わないでしょ？
One-way ticket is fine, right?
無理も通せば道理がなんちゃら
When pushing the impossible, reason becomes...
高く高く跳べる気がしてるんだ
I feel like I can jump higher and higher
きらきら、光っているはずなんだ
Sparkling, it should be shining
キャパシティオーバー
Capacity over!
てんてこまいの毎日だ
Hectic every single day
頭ごんがらだって warning warning
Head getting all tangled up, warning, warning
でっかい月の上にウサギがいるんだっけ？
Is there a rabbit on top of the big moon?
宇宙旅行にパスポートって要りますか？
Do you need a passport for space travel?
僕らが暮らしてるセカイの明日はどんな色？
What color is tomorrow in the world we live in?
君と僕で描いていくふたりいろ
The two-tone colors we paint together
I shall checkmate 君を checkmate
I shall checkmate, I'm gonna checkmate you
地球の裏から夢の中まで
From the other side of the earth to deep in dreams
ひらひら、スカートが揺れる
Our skirts sway in harmony
escort 君を escort
Escort, I'll be your escort
マニュアル通りじゃつまらないでしょ？
Following the manual isn't fun, right?
不安の数だけ希望があるってこと
There's as much hope as there is anxiety
きらきら、光っているはずなんだ
Sparkling, it should be shining
エマージェンシーじゃん
It's an emergency!
なんでもありのアイドルだ
An idol who can do anything
常識もグラついちゃって panic panic
Common sense wobbles, panic, panic
深海、海の底でマーメイドが恋をしたって？
Did a mermaid fall in love at the bottom of the sea?
嘘か本当か確かめにいきませんか？
Shall we go check if it's true or not?
僕らの暮らしてるセカイは人ひとりひとつの色
Our world is made of each person's unique color
それはお父さんお母さんのあいどいろ
That's Mom and Dad's love color
I shall checkmate 君を checkmate
I shall checkmate, I'm gonna checkmate you
雨降り天気でも会いにいくよ
I'll go see you even in rainy weather
果報が来るまで寝とけばいいってマジ？
Seriously, just sleep until good fortune comes?
いやいや、待てるわけなくてね
No way, I can't wait!
絶好調、もうずっと絶好調
In top form, always in top form
片道切符で構わないでしょ？
A one-way ticket is fine, right?
理不尽も通せば道理がなんややら
Unreason becomes reason if pushed far enough
高く高く跳べる気がしてるんだ
I feel like I can jump higher and higher
胸の奥がキュッとなる
My chest tightens up
消せない消せない過去も笑えるように
So we can laugh even at unforgetting pasts
未来が僕らを呼んでる
The future is calling us
ほら踊れる曲は踊っ とくのが楽しむコツ
Dancing to the song is the key to having fun
I shall checkmate 君を checkmate
I shall checkmate, I'm gonna checkmate you
会いたい時には会いにいくよ
I'll go see you when I want to see you
机の奥から22世紀まで
From deep inside the desk to the 22nd century
ふらふら、旅してる途中
Wandering, in the middle of a journey
escort 君を escort
Escort, I'll be your escort
マニュアル通りじゃつまらないでしょ？
Following the manual isn't fun, right?
不安の数だけ希望があるってこと
There's as much hope as there is anxiety
高く高く跳べる気がしてる
I feel like I can jump higher and higher
きらきら、光っているはずなんだ
Sparkling, it should be shining
パタパタと便りがしげ るんだ
Letters flutter densely
片道切符でこまらないでしょ？
A one-way ticket won't be a problem, right?
不安の数だけ希望があってこそ
Hope exists precisely because of anxiety
パタパタと便りがしげ るんだ
Letters flutter densely
キラキラ光って いるはずなんだ
It should be shining bright
I shall checkmate 君を checkmate
I shall checkmate, I'm gonna checkmate you
会いたい時には会いにいくよ
I'll go see you when I want to see you
机の奥から22世紀まで
From deep inside the desk to the 22nd century
escort 君を escort
Escort, I'll be your escort
ここまでいろんな村を旅してきたでござるが、
We've traveled through various villages up until now,
世界にはいろんな人がいるでござるな。
there are so many different people in this world.
きっとまだまだ風真の知らないことがきっといっぱいあるでござるな。
I'm sure there are still so many things I don't know yet.
あ、北に二つ前の村でいただいたあの紫色ナスっていう野菜は、まことに、まことに美味いであったな。
Ah, that purple eggplant we got in the village two stops north was truly, truly delicious.
またどこかで食べる機会があれば、絶対たくさん食べよ、で……
If I ever get the chance to eat it again, I'll definitely eat a ton, and...
お、そんなこと言ってる場合じゃない。さっさと次の村を目指して。
Oh, this is no time to be saying that. I must head to the next village.
今日もルロー侍は勝寺にあるのみ！目指すは侍ナンバーワンでござる！
Today too, Ruro Samurai is all about winning! Aiming to be Samurai Number One!
まあ、風真のこのフィジカルを持っていればどんな敵もどんな危険もへっちゃらでござるけど、
Well, with my physical strength, any enemy or danger is a breeze, but...
やっぱ心配だな。1人で行くのは怖いし。
Still, I'm worried. Going alone is scary.
あ、そ、そういう時のポコべ…お、お、ポコべ？
Ah, th-those times when Pokobe... o-oh, Pokobe?
あ、もうまたポコべ、はぐれてしまったでござるか？
Ah, Pokobe got separated from me again?
え、いないの？いなくなっちゃったじゃん！
Eh, not here? He's gone!
もう、今日は風の匂いもあり、おてんとさまも陰ってきたし、
Geez, today there's the smell of wind, the sun has clouded over,
どこへ行ったでござるか？
where on earth did he go?
って、やば！いってるそばから雨でござるか？
Wait, oh no! Is it starting to rain right as I say that?
まったくもう、ポコべ！どこ行ったでござるか？ポコべ！
Good grief, Pokobe! Where did you go, Pokobe?!
なんか寒くなってきたし、そのうちが恋しいでござる。ポコべ、どこだよー！
It's getting cold, and I miss home. Pokobe, where are you?!
先の見えないルローの旅。この先何者になってどう生きればいいんだろうか。
The invisible journey of a wanderer. What will I become, and how should I live?
いつか風真も誰かの支えになれる日が来るのだろうか。こんな世界……
Will the day ever come when I can be someone's support? Such a world...
「こんな世界」と嘆く誰かの
In this world crying,
生きる理由になれるでしょうか
could I become someone's reason to live?
これは僕が今君に贈る
This is what I send to you now,
最初で最後の愛の言葉だ
the first and last words of love.
街も人も歪み出した
The city and people distorted,
けものだと気付いたんだ
I realized they were monsters.
欲動に巣食った愚かさも
The stupidity eaten by greed,
全てがこの目に映る
everything is reflected in my eyes.
シアトリカルに手の上で
Everyone is made to dance
誰をも彼をも踊らせる
on the hands of the theatric.
生まれた意味だって知らぬまま
Not knowing the meaning of birth,
形骸化した夢は錆びついてしまった
the fossilized dream has rusted away.
「愛をください」
"Please give me love,"
きっと誰もがそう願った
I'm sure everyone hoped so.
「愛をください」
"Please give me love,"
そっと震えた手を取って
please take my trembling hand gently.
「愛をください」
"Please give me love,"
心を揺るぐ醜いくらいに美しい愛を
give me love so beautiful it shakes the heart.
「こんな世界」と嘆く誰かの
In this world crying,
生きる理由になれるでしょうか
could I be someone's reason to live?
いつか終わると気づいた日から
Since the day I realized it would end,
詩へと秒を読む心臓だ
my heart counts the seconds into a poem.
永遠なんてないけど
There is no eternity,
思い通りの日々じゃないけど
though days aren't as I imagined.
もろく弱い糸につながれた
Bound by a fragile, weak thread,
次の夜明けがまた訪れる
the next dawn will come again.
どんな世界も君がいるなら
In any world, with you in it,
生きていたいって思えたんだよ
I felt I wanted to keep living.
僕の地獄で君はいつでも
In my own hell, you are always
絶えず駆動する心臓だ
a heart beating endlessly.
ねえこのまま雨に溺れて
Hey, drowning in the rain like this,
愛に溶けたって構わないから
I don't care if I melt into love.
どうかどうかまたあの日のように
Please, just like that day,
傘を差し出して笑って見せてよ
open your umbrella and smile for me.
もしもし夢が覚めなければ
If only I hadn't woken from the dream,
姿を変えずにいられた？
could I have stayed unchanged?
ほぐれた指から消える温度
Warmth fading from loosened fingers,
血を巡らせるのは誰の思い出？
whose memories circulate the blood?
雨に濡れた配線
Wires drenched in rain,
すすけた病室並んだ装飾灯
soot-stained hospital decorations,
夕暮れのバス停
a bus stop at dusk,
止まったままの観覧車
a Ferris wheel frozen in place.
机に咲く花君の声も
Flowers blooming on the desk, your voice,
何もかも
and everything else
最初からなかったみたい
felt like it was never there at all.
しにたい僕は今日も息をして
Wanting to die, I breathe today too,
生きたい君は明日を見失って
while you, wanting to live, lost sight of tomorrow.
なのにどうして悲しいのだろう
Why is it that I feel so sad?
いずれ滅ぶのが人間だ
Humans are bound to perish eventually.
永遠なんてないけど
There is no eternity,
思い通りの日々じゃないけど
though days aren't as I imagined.
もろく弱い糸につながれた
Bound by a fragile, weak thread,
次の夜明けがまた訪れる
the next dawn will come again.
どんな世界も君がいるなら生きていたいって思えたんだよ
In any world, with you in it, I felt I wanted to keep living.
僕の地獄で君はいつでも
In my own hell, you are always
絶えず駆動する心臓だ
a heart beating endlessly.
いつしか君がくれたように
Just like you once gave me,
僕も
I too...
誰かの心臓になれたなら
If I could become someone's heart.
しにたい僕は今日も息をして
Wanting to die, I breathe today too,
生きたい君は明日を見失って
while you, wanting to live, lost sight of tomorrow.
どんな世界も君がいるなら
In any world, with you in it,
生きていたいって思えたんだよ
I felt I wanted to keep living.
僕の地獄で君はいつでも
In my own hell, you are always
絶えず駆動する心臓だ
a heart beating endlessly.
ああ永遠なんてないけど
Ah, there is no eternity,
思い通りの日々じゃないけど
though days aren't as I imagined.
もろく弱い糸につながれた
Bound by a fragile, weak thread,
次の夜明けがまた訪れる
the next dawn will come again.
どんな世界も君がいるなら
In any world, with you in it,
生きていたいって思えたんだよ
I felt I wanted to keep living.
僕の地獄で君はいつでも
In my own hell, you are always
絶えず駆動する心臓だ
a heart beating endlessly.
ああいつしか君がくれたように
Ah, just like you once gave me,
僕も
I too...
誰かの心臓になれたなら
If I could become someone's heart.
しにたい僕は今日も息をして
Wanting to die, I breathe today too,
生きたい君は明日を見失って
while you, wanting to live, lost sight of tomorrow.
なのにどうして悲しいのだろう
Why is it that I feel so sad?
いずれ滅ぶのが人間だ
Humans are bound to perish eventually.
ああいつしか君がくれたように
Ah, just like you once gave me,
僕も
I too...
誰かの心臓になれたなら
If I could become someone's heart.
誰か
Someone...
あ、ポコビー！
Ah, Pokobee!
よかった、無事でござるか？
Thank goodness, are you safe?
もう本当に探したんですよ！無事ですか？
I've been looking everywhere for you! Are you okay?
よかった……。
Thank goodness...
ねぇ、ポコビー。
Hey, Pokobee.
風真は誰かのためになれるかなぁ？
Wonder if I can be there for someone?
え？ 何？ 何々？
Eh? What? What is it?
あ、外の世界には風真を必要とする仲間が必ずいる？本当 に？
Ah, in the outside world, there are comrades who need me? Really?
うーん、そでござるか？
Hmm, is that so?
え、何？
Eh, what?
あ、それに、外の世界にはたくさんの面白い身のこともある待ってる？
Ah, and in the outside world, lots of interesting things are waiting?
確かに！
That's true!
そうかもしれないでござれな。
That might just be the case.
確かにそんな気がしてきた！ポコビー、ありがとでござる！
I'm starting to feel that way! Pokobee, thank you!
あ、そんな話してたら見て！雨もやんだ、晴れてきたでござる！
Ah, while talking about that, look! The rain stopped, it's clearing up!
そうだよね。まだまだ知らないこといっぱいあるから、見に行かなきゃいけないでござるよな。
That's right. There's still so much we don't know, so we have to go see it.
よし！
Alright!
まだまだね、知らないことを一緒に探しに行くでござる。
We're going to go find things we don't know together.
まだ見ぬ仲間を探しに共に歩んでいくでござる！
We'll walk together to find unseen comrades!
何回言っても聞く耳持たない 不勉強アウトサイダー
Not listening no matter how many times I say it, unstudious outsider
廊下全力ダッシュそこの君止まりなさい だから止まりなさい
Running full speed down the hallway, stop right there! I said stop right there!
あーうるさいなんだよ 急いでんだよ わざわざ暇なんですか?
Ah, how annoying, what is it, I'm in a rush, are you doing this out of sheer boredom?
誰もいないしこれくらいいいだろ 君に構う暇はないからじゃあね
There's no one around, so a little is fine, right? I don't have time to deal with you, see ya!
ちょっ、聞いてんの? 風紀を乱すなって言ってんの
Hey hey, are you listening? I'm telling you not to disrupt public morals!
まー聞く気はないけどね お前なんかめちゃ嫌い!
Well, I have no intention of listening. I hate you so much!
怒っちゃってんのあーらざみろ いや絶対に俺の方が上って言って競ってまたギラギラ
Are you mad? Ha, serves you right! No, saying I'm better than you, competing and glaring again
一体なんの為になるのやら 勤勉真面目ヤクザ
What on earth is the point of any of it? You hyper-studious, serious yakuza
少しルール破ったくらいで キレすぎだろ
Getting this mad just over breaking a few rules, you're way too persistent
あーほらまたやってるまた破ってる 学習してないようでさ
Ah, look, you're doing it again, breaking them, acting like you never learn
シャツも出てるわネクタイ緩いわ 親の顔が見てみたいもんですわ
Your shirt is untucked, your tie is loose, I'd love to see what your parents look like
今度したら絶対許しません お前なんかめちゃ嫌い!
If you do it next time, I will never forgive you! I hate you so much!
怒っちゃいるが笑顔は隠せない
You're mad, but you can't hide your smile!
いや絶対に仲良しとかしないって言って拗ねてまたゲラゲラ
No, saying we'd never get along like that, glaring and laughing out loud again
ヘイヘイ坊っちゃんちゅん捕まえてごらんなさ
Hey hey young master, try catching me if you can!
だから廊下は走るなって何回言えば
That's why I've told you so many times not to run in the hallway!
なあどうした優等生 負けを認めますか どうやら全く反省してないようですね
Hey, what's wrong, honor student, do you admit defeat? It seems you haven't reflected on this at all.
ねえねえちょっと聞いてんの 頭に血でも上っちゃってんの
Hey hey, are you listening to me? Has the blood rushed to your head?
あーはいはいもう分かりました もうブチ切れちゃうからね
Ah, yes yes, I understand now. I'm going to totally snap!
有りったけ全部巻き込んでドタバタ 破壊転倒非行でめちゃくちゃ
Involving everything all at once, in a chaotic uproar, with destruction, vandalism, and delinquency, making a complete mess
もう一切のものは見ずに一つの敵と戦うのだ
Without looking at a single thing, fighting a single enemy
いやマジでお前なんかめちゃ嫌い!
No, seriously, I hate you so much!
この先もずっとずっと嫌いだい!
I'll hate you forever and ever from now on!
で制裁食らって 仲直りって言った五秒後にはメラメラ
Then taking punishment, and five seconds after saying "let's make up," blazing up again!
何回言っても聞く耳持たない 不勉強アウトサイダー
Not listening no matter how many times I say it, unstudious outsider
廊下全力ダッシュそこの君止まりなさい だから止まりなさい
Running full speed down the hallway, stop right there! I said stop right there!
あーうるさいなんだよ 急いでんだよ わざわざ暇なんですか?
Ah, how annoying, what is it, I'm in a rush, are you doing this out of sheer boredom?
誰もいないしこれくらいいいだろ 君に構う暇はないからじゃあね
There's no one around, so a little is fine, right? I don't have time to deal with you, see ya!
ちょっ、聞いてんの? 頭に血でも上っちゃってんの
Hey hey, are you listening? Has the blood rushed to your head?
あーはいはいもう分かりました もうブチ切れちゃうからね
Ah, yes yes, I understand now. I'm going to totally snap!
有りったけ全部巻き込んでドタバタ 破壊転倒非行でめちゃくちゃ
Involving everything all at once, in a chaotic uproar, with destruction, vandalism, and delinquency, making a complete mess
赤い旋風飛行でめちゃくちゃ もう一切のものは見ずに一つの敵と戦うのだ
Flying in a red whirlwind, making a complete mess, without looking at a single thing, fighting a single enemy
いやマジでお前なんかめちゃ嫌い!
No, seriously, I hate you so much!
この先もずっとずっと嫌いだい!
I'll hate you forever and ever from now on!
全然反省してなさそうなのにって言った五秒後にはメラメラ
Even though it seems you haven't reflected at all, five seconds later you're blazing up again
メラメラ…
Blazing up...
右肩に紫蝶々 微笑み蝶々
A purple butterfly on my right shoulder, smiling butterfly
接吻をした この部屋の隅で切ないと云う感情を知る
Kissed in this corner of the room, I come to know the painful emotion
ぴっぴぴあの 不協和音
The discordant sound of the piano
右肩の蝶
Butterfly on my right shoulder
右肩に紫蝶々 微笑み蝶々
A purple butterfly on my right shoulder, smiling butterfly
接吻をした
Kissed
右肩に紫蝶々
A purple butterfly on my right shoulder,
キスをしたこの部屋の隅で
In the corner of this room where we kissed,
切ないと云う感情を知る
I know the feeling of agony.
響くピアノ 不協和音
A piano echoes, a dissonant sound.
悪い夢にうなされた私を早く起こして
Wake me up quickly from this nightmare that haunted me.
どんなことでも始まりは些細なことでしょう?
No matter what, beginnings are always trivial, right?
どこがいいかなんて聞かれても困る
Even if you ask me what's good, I'm at a loss,
綺麗な夜に惑わされたまま行方不明だから
Bewitched by the beautiful night, I'm missing.
長いまつげ 三日月アイライン
Long eyelashes, a crescent moon eyeliner,
まぶたに乗せて光るリップ
Resting on my eyelids, shining lips.
抱き寄せた 歪んだ体埋めるのは
Holding me close, to fill my distorted body,
あなたしかいない
there is only you.
この部屋の隅で キスをした
In the corner of this room where we kissed...
感情を知る 響くピアノ 不協和音
I know the feeling, a piano echoes, dissonance.
悪い夢にうなされた私を
Wake me up quickly from the nightmare...
雨の中を濡れた髪を 異常に爪で引っ掻いて
Soaking in the rain, scratching my drenched hair with nails,
寂しさをトイレに吐き出して震えて待ってる
Vomiting my loneliness into the toilet, trembling and waiting.
追いかけては逃げる からそれ以上をで返しして
Chasing and running away, give me back even more than that—
真剣だから笑う 似た者同士に出会うより
Since we're serious, we laugh, rather than meeting kindred spirits.
赤い爪とヤツモモ指は 傷つく度増えるピアス
Red nails and thighs... piercings that increase with every wound.
抱き寄せた 歪んだ体埋めるのは あなたしかいない
Holding me close, only you can fill this distorted body.
そうでしょう? わかってるくせに 今日も境界線越えてる
Right? You know it, yet you're crossing the line today.
後悔は死ぬほどしてる その分だけ快感を呼び覚ます
I regret it to death, and that alone awakens the pleasure.
狂いだした 私を止めて 一瞬でラクにしてよ
Stop me as I start to go mad, and release me in an instant.
傷口なら溶け出したものは 愛情それとも…
What melted from the wound? Is it affection, or...?
後悔は死ぬほどしてる その分だけ快感を呼び覚ます
I regret it to death, and that alone awakens the pleasure.
狂いだした 私を止めて 一瞬でラクにしてよ
Stop me as I start to go mad, and release me in an instant.
そうでしょう? わかってるくせに 境界線とっくに越えてる
Right? You know it, yet you've crossed the line long ago.
後悔は死ぬほどしてる その分だけ快感を呼び覚ます
I regret it to death, and that alone awakens the pleasure.
右肩に紫蝶々
A purple butterfly on my right shoulder,
キスをしたこの部屋の隅で
In the corner of this room where we kissed,
切ないと云う感情を知る
I know the feeling of agony.
響くピアノ 不協和音
A piano echoes, a dissonant sound.
悪い夢にうなされた私を早く起こして
Wake me up quickly from this nightmare that haunted me.
こよちゃんへ いつも元気でがんばり屋さん。
To Koyori-chan: Always energetic and a hard worker.
こよちゃんはかざまにとって正直、憧れでした。
To Kazama, Koyori-chan has honestly been an aspiration.
がんばる姿に元気をもらってます。
I get so much energy from seeing you work hard.
一昨日もポストで緊張してるかざまにエールをありがとう。
Thank you for cheering on a nervous Kazama via post the day before yesterday too.
いつも引っ張ってくれて優しくて頼りになるこよちゃんが、かざまに相談事をしてくれた時すごくうれしかったです！
When Koyori-chan—who always leads me, is kind, and dependable—asked me for advice, I was so, so happy!
またいつでも頼ってね。
Count on me anytime again, okay?
いつもありがとう。大好きだよ。
Thank you as always. I love you!
ポッピンキャンディ☆フィーバー！
Poppin' Candy Fever!
あの日忘れた夢色も
The dream-colored hues I forgot that day...
あの日 忘れた 夢色も
Even the dream colors I forgot that day,
昨日 躓いた 涙色も
And the tear colors I tripped over yesterday,
ありのままでいいよね
Can't be said as they are, right?
だから とっておきの魔法をかけよう
So let's cast a special magic spell.
キャラメル・キャンディ・チョコレート
Caramel, candy, chocolate,
お洒落でカワイイティータイムは
A stylish and cute tea time
なんか疲れちゃいそうだし
Seems like it'd make me tired, so
アゲアゲで行こうよ
Let's go high-energy!
アゲアゲ！
High-energy!
コツは楽しんで楽しもう
The trick is to enjoy and have fun,
もちろん何でもアリです当然でしょ？
Of course anything goes, naturally, right?
ていうか振りかぶるくらいがストライク
I mean, winding up big is a strike!
無敵になれちゃうね！
We can become invincible!
チン・ドン・シャンのリズムで
To the rhythm of chin-don-shan,
忘れないで君のBGM
Don't forget your background music.
甘い匂いに釣られたなら
If you were lured by a sweet scent,
それじゃみんな！宴の幕開けだ！
Then everyone! The banquet begins!
ポッピンキャンディ☆フィーバー！
Poppin' Candy Fever!
弾けちゃえフレーバー
Bursting flavor!
party party なんて言うんです
party party, you could say.
Shall We Dance?
なんナンだってフィーバー！？
What kind of fever is this!?
兎も角もさわしわし踊り明かそ
Anyway, let's dance all night long.
ポッピンキャンディ☆アップル！？
Poppin' Candy Apple!?
ねぇ聞いてよ dreamer
Hey, listen to me, dreamer!
check it! check it! なんて言うんです
check it! check it! you could say.
Shall We Dance?
なんてだってフィーバー！
What a fever!
テンションはワックスでもっともっと溶けちゃうくらい
Tension is maxed out, enough to melt away more and more!
歌え！
Sing!
ちゃちゃちゃ！
Cha-cha-cha!
踊れ！
Dance!
いぇいいぇい！
Yeah yeah!
笑え！
Smile!
はっはっは！
Ha ha ha!
まあいい感じ！
Well, feels good!
ねぇもう一回！ちゃちゃちゃ！
Hey, once more! Cha-cha-cha!
もういいかい？いいよ！
Ready yet? Ready!
問題！？きゃーー！で
No problem!? Kyaaa! And
はい優勝！イエーイ！
Yes, victory! Yay!
煌めく空をなぞったら
If you trace the sparkling sky,
ほんのちょっと寂しくなるね
It gets just a little bit lonely, right?
それじゃあケーキもおひとつどうぞ？
Then how about a piece of cake too?
なんだか笑えてきたね
Somehow we started laughing, didn't we?
ピンクの勘が響くよは
Pink intuition resonates,
耳を澄ませば君のBGM
If you listen closely, your BGM.
お腹の合図が聞こえたら
If you hear the signal from your tummy,
それじゃみんな！うさぎの再会だ！
Then everyone! The reunion of rabbits!
ポッピンキャンディ☆フィーバー！
Poppin' Candy Fever!
シュワシュワフレーバー
Fizzy flavor!
ポッチポッチなんて言うんです
Pocchi-pocchi, you could say.
Shall We Dance?
なんナンだってフィーバー！
What a fever!
夢の出口を見失ってそう
Losing sight of the exit of dreams,
わしわし踊り明かそう
Let's dance all night long.
ポッピンキャンディ☆プレス！
Poppin' Candy Press!
こっち向いて dreamer
Look this way, dreamer!
ハリハリアップルなんて言うんです
Hari-hari apple, you could say.
Shall We Dance?
大味はミックスでもっともっと楽しんじゃって
The rich taste is mixed, so enjoy it more and more!
もういっかい行けるね？おかえり！
Can we go once more? Welcome back!
あの日 忘れた 夢色も
Even the dream colors I forgot that day,
ポッピンキャンディ☆フィーバー！
Poppin' Candy Fever!
弾けちゃえフレーバー
Bursting flavor!
party party なんて言うんです
party party, you could say.
Shall We Dance?
恥ずかしがり屋でも
What kind of fever is this!?
わしわし踊り明かそう
Anyway, let's dance all night long.
ポッピンキャンディ☆ピーチ！？
Poppin' Candy Peach!?
ねぇ聞いてよ dreamer
Hey, listen to me, dreamer!
check it! check it! なんて言うんです
check it! check it! you could say.
Shall We Dance?
なんてだってフィーバー！
What a fever!
テンションはワックスでもっともっと溶けちゃうくらい
Tension is maxed out, enough to melt away more and more!
歌え！ちゃちゃちゃ！踊れ！いぇいいぇい！
Sing! Cha-cha-cha! Dance! Yeah yeah!
笑え！はっはっは！まあいい感じ！
Smile! Ha ha ha! Well, feels good!
ねぇもう一回！ちゃちゃちゃ！もういいかい？いいよ！
Hey, once more! Cha-cha-cha! Ready yet? Ready!
問題！？はい優勝！イエーイ！
No problem!? Yes, victory! Yay!
Poppin' Candy★Fever!
Poppin' Candy Fever!
クロエへ
つらい時、つらいと言えないかざまに気がついて声をかけてくれたのはクロエでした。
To Chloe,\
When I was going through hard times and couldn't say so, you noticed and spoke to me, Chloe.
あの時話しかけてくれた事
本当にうれしかったよ。
I was truly happy\
that you talked to me back then.
いつも話がきいてくれて
話をきかせてくれて、ありがとう。
Thank you for always listening to me\
and letting me listen to you.
あの執念の告知ポストの真似も
実は結構うれしかったです。
And honestly, mimicking that obsessive announcement post\
made me really happy too.
優しくて努力家なクロエが
かざまは大好きです。
Kazama loves you,\
kind and hardworking Chloe.
ジェヘナ
Gehenna
なぁ 元気？調子はどうだい？
Hey, how are you? How's it going?
あぁ もうね そういうのやめたんだ
Yeah, well, I quit that kind of stuff.
うん なんかもう回復の見込みはないそうなんだ
Yeah, looks like there's no hope of recovery anymore.
何も聞かないでくれ
Don't ask me about anything.
応答 根踏み 断症 会
Response, calculation, diagnosis meeting...
介護 悦 共有もサレンダーだ
Caregiving, joy, sharing—I surrender all.
はい そうです 正真正銘 僕のせいだった
Yes, that's right, 100% it was my fault.
よくある話 単純明快をモノにしたくて
A common story, wanting to make simplicity my own,
格あるべきという理想を殺して
I killed the ideal of how things ought to be.
もう散々だって逃げる勇気もない
I've had enough, yet I don't have the courage to run.
はやく もっと 墜ちて
Hurry, falling even deeper—
毎夜 喉を塞ぐ透明の概要
Every night, the transparent summary suffocates my throat.
肺を蝕む存在も
Even the reality that caves in my lungs...
なあ 元気?
Hey, you fine?
調子はどうだい?
Is everything alright?
ああ もうね
Well, lately...
そういうの辞めたんだ
I've stopped doing that.
うん
Yeah...
なんか もう回復の見込みはなさそうなんだ
It seems I can't see a point to hope anymore.
僕らは生きるしかないんだ
We have no choice but to survive.
おい お前
Hey, you there?
そっちはどうだい?
Are you still doing alright?
ああ まだ
Ah, I see...
そんなことやってんだ
You're still doing such things?
そういや
Yeah...
付き合ってたとはどうなったんだ?
What happened to the one you used to date?
何も言わないでくれ
Don't say anything anymore.
将来 妬み 敗北感 ワイアレス
Future, envy, failure, wireless...
首も吊れないな
Can't even hang myself up.
はい 上手
Yes, how nice...
大変身に染みるお話でした
It was a story that seeped into my body.
満たされたかい?
Are you satisfied now?
真っ黒に奪われた心も
My poor heart is clouded in pitch black.
アルコールでそっと過剰にして眠ろう
Softly and excessively sleeping with alcohol.
もう跡形もない可哀想な水になって
Becoming pathetic water without a trace.
もっと もっと 堕ちて
More and more, falling...
生きていたいよ
I wanna stay alive each night.
喉を塞ぐ透明な概略も
The air and future keep their grip around my throat.
理不尽も 孤独も
Unreasonable things and loneliness...
恨まなくていい
You don't gotta hate them.
それら全部意味はないんだ
Cuz no matter what, they don't have any meaning.
僕らは生きるしかないんだ
We have no choice but to survive.
生きていたいよ
I wanna stay alive.
なんでかわからないけど
Why? I don't know, but...
生きてたよ
I wanna stay alive.
ディーネーという聖書
A scripture called DEENEE.
本能のまま今日も不毛に生きていい
Instinctively living ominously today as well.
どうせ何も変わらないんだ
Cuz nothing will change anyway.
生きていたいよ
I wanna stay alive.
なんの希望もないけど
With no hope at all...
生きていたいよ
I wanna stay alive.
本能は腹打つのも
Instincts are striking back too.
生きていたいよ
I wanna stay alive.
生きていたかったよ
I wanted to stay alive.
本当にはそんなんなんだけど
Truth is, that's all there is.
僕らは生きるしかないんだ
We have no choice but to survive.
騙してごめんよ
I'm sorry I deceived you.
言えなくてごめんよ
I'm sorry I couldn't tell you.
本当悲しいけれど
And this is so sad.
苦しいだけが絆なんだ
Only suffering is the bond.
なあ 元気? 調子はどうだい?
Hey, you fine? Is everything alright?
ああ もうね そういうの辞めたんだ
Well, lately, I've stopped doing that one thing.
うん なんか もう回復の見込みはなさそうなんだ
Yeah, it seems that I can't see a point to hope.
ずっと探してたんだよ
I've been searching for it all this time...
特別だって言える場所
A place I can call special.
なんで僕を選んだの
Why did you choose me?
笑うキミが手を引いたんだ
The smiling you took my hand.
だってキミはすごいから
Because you are amazing,
負けないなって思うんだよ
I think I can't afford to lose.
どんな時も僕の中に
At any time, deep inside me...
キミの声が鳴り響いていた
Your voice was echoing.
怖いんだ
I was scared.
なにもない僕だけどできるかな
I'm just a nobody, but can I do it?
自信のなさとしょうまなさで一生を過ごすけど
Living with self-doubt and silliness...
キミは「それがどうしたの?」って顔をして
You put on a smile and said, "What was that about?"
歌を歌うじゃない それはズルいじゃない?
"Not singing a song? Isn't that unfair?"
飛び込んでいこう 僕らのセカイへ
Let's dive in, to our sekai!
正解の想いに出会えるかな
Can we meet the right thoughts?
歌っていたい 踊っていたい
I want to keep singing, keep dancing,
痛いくらい笑えるように
So I can smile until it hurts.
名前もない僕らのセカイを
Our nameless sekai...
迷っていけるよキミとだから
We can wander through, because it's with you.
変わっていこう願うように
Let's change, as we wish.
今僕ら 期待の未体験を
Now, we'll experience the expected unknown!
キミの未来を僕が歌うよ 描いてもっと Yeah
I will sing your future, drawing it even more, yeah.
泣いてもいいじゃん それも答えだ
It's fine to cry, that's also an answer.
どうしたっていいよ 想いは全部零さぬように抱き締めながら
Whatever is fine, holding them tight so none are lost...
キミと見たいセカイへ
To the world I want to see with you
ずっと探してたんだよ
I've always been searching for it,
特別だって言える場所
a place I can call special.
どんな僕になるんだろう
What kind of self will I become?
踊るココロ変えないように
So my dancing heart doesn't change,
ちょっとだけのその先で
just a little bit beyond that,
また笑えるよ
I can smile again.
もらったバトンは勇気に
The baton I received into courage,
ありがとうは歌声に
"thank you" into a singing voice—
気づいたんだ
I realized
僕にしか出来ないこともあること
that there are things only I can do,
誰かのとこへちゃんと歌を届けたいのさ
and I want to deliver my song to someone.
ほら
Come on,
怖くて震える手でビート刻めば
if you beat with trembling hands,
夢も近いじゃない？僕らひとりじゃない
isn't the dream close? We're not alone.
飛び込んでいこう 僕らのセカイへ
Let's dive into our world,
正解の想いに出会えるかな
to see if we'll encounter true feelings.
歌っていたい
I want to keep singing,
踊っていたい
I want to keep dancing,
痛いくらい笑えるように
so I can laugh until it hurts.
名前もない僕らの世界を
We can wander through our nameless world
迷っていけるよ キミとだから
because I'm with you.
変わっていこう 願うように
Let's change, as we wish,
今僕ら 期待の未体験を
right now into expected uncharted territory.
歌っていたい
I want to keep singing,
踊っていたい
I want to keep dancing,
痛いくらい笑えるように
so I can laugh until it hurts.
名前もない僕らの世界を
We can wander through our nameless world
迷っていけるよ キミとだから
because I'm with you.
変わっていこう 願うように
Let's change, as we wish,
今僕ら 期待の未体験を
right now into expected uncharted territory.
キミの未来を僕が歌うよ
I'll sing of your future.
描いてもっと Yeah
Draw it out even more, yeah!
泣いてもいいじゃん それも答えだ
It's okay to cry, that's also an answer.
どうしたっていいよ 想いは全部
No matter what, let's embrace all
こぼさぬように 抱きしめながら
our feelings so they don't spill,
キミと見たいセカイへ
to the world I want to see with you.
To the world I want to see with you...
キミと見たいセカイへ
To the world I want to see with you!
はい！みなさんこんばんはでござる！
Hi everyone, good evening, de zaru!
ここまでの風真いろは物語、いかがだったでしょうか？
How was the Kazama Iroha story up to this point?
ただの侍から、いろんな大切な仲間に出会い、ホロライブという世界にやってきて、ホロックスの風真いろはになりました！わあーい！ござる！
From just a samurai, meeting various precious friends, coming to Hololive, and becoming Hololive's Kazama Iroha! Yay! De zaru!
ござる！
De zaru!
しょうがないけど、ドキドキですね、
It can't be helped, but I'm so nervous.
ここまでいろんな道を歩んできたのですが、風真いろはがホロライブに入る前のイフストーリーということで、やらせていただきました！ありがとうございます！
Up to now, I've walked various paths, and as an if-story before joining Hololive, I was allowed to do this! Thank you very much!
そして嬉しいことに、今Xのトレンドで、この風真いろは2周年ライブ、これ1位になってるみたいです！本当にかざがとうございます！大変恐縮です！
And happily, right now on X, this Kazama Iroha 2nd Anniversary Live is number one! Thank you so much! I am deeply humbled!
はい、ということでですね、色々あるんですけど、今回はその物語に沿って、今回ステージを作っていただきました！かっこいい！演劇っぽいこのステージになっております！また詳しい話はですね、別日であふたーとーくさせていただければなと思います。
Yes, so, following that story, they made this stage for us! So cool! It feels like a play. We can talk about the details in an after-talk on another day.
そしてそして、ここまでですね、ちょっと不慣れなんですが、ホロックスに対しての手紙と一緒に歌って踊りやらせていただきました！なんとこちらのホロックスとのコラボ、後ろでMVが流れていましたね！そう、そういうことなんです。現在の曲たち4曲ですね、鋭意製作中で素敵しだい投稿するので、みんなね楽しみにしていてください！
And up to here, I'm a bit unaccustomed, but along with a letter to Holox, I sang and danced! And look, the MV was playing in the back! The current four songs are in production and will be posted soon, so please look forward to it!
ちょっとね、お水きゅっきゅして、まだまだダンスするから、ちょっと、あとチャキ丸と羽織り置いてくるわ。あっつすぎるでござる！
Let me have a quick sip of water, I'll still dance more, so wait, I'll go leave Chakimaru and my haori. It's way too hot, de zaru!
それではですねみなと、今風真いろははホロックスの風真いろはになったところで、今日は2周年ライブというライブなので、やっぱりアイドルらしくて、この、アイドルらしくて、このあともガンガン盛り上げて
Well then everyone, now that Kazama Iroha is Holox's Kazama Iroha, today's live is a 2nd anniversary live, so as an idol, we'll keep hyping it up from here on!
次行きますよ！
Let's go to the next one!
それでは皆さんの準備はいいですか？
So, is everyone ready?
次の曲いきます。
We're going to the next song.
次の曲は、ヒロイン育成計画！
The next song is Heroine Training Plan!
きっとヒロインなら綺麗で
I'm sure if you're a heroine, you're pretty,
王子様にチヤホヤされるでしょ？
and pampered by princes, right?
芋女の私もお姫様になれたらなんてね
It'd be nice if a plain girl like me could be a princess...
イェイ！
Yeah!
バイト探し 採用ないし
Looking for a part-time job, no hires,
やけになって飛び込む 場違いすぎる世界
so I recklessly jumped into a totally out-of-place world.
パシリばかり 雑用係
Running errands everywhere, acting as a chore girl,
最悪の奴らのマネージャー就任です
I've been appointed manager of the worst guys.
バレたら最後 罷免されるでしょ？
If it gets exposed, I'll be fired, right?
秘密の私もお姫様になれたらなんてね
If my secret self could become a princess too...
きっとヒロインなら綺麗で
I'm sure if you're a heroine, you're pretty,
王子様にチヤホヤされるでしょ？
and pampered by princes, right?
秘密の私もお姫様になれたらなんてね
It'd be nice if secret me could become a princess too...
私もプロデュースして
Produce me too,
髪も服も全部可愛くして
make my hair and clothes all cute.
いつか出会う王子様どこで何をしてるの神様
Prince I'll meet someday, where and what are you doing, God?
待ってますから気長に
I'll wait patiently,
ある日出会う運命の人
One day, I meet the person of my destiny,
紳士な振る舞いにドキドキしちゃったんだ
and my heart raced at his gentlemanly behavior.
名前なんて聞けるはずない
There's no way I could ask for his name,
また会いたいなんて願ってるだけでした
I was just wishing I could see him again.
時間が止まる「また会えたね」と君やっぱり恋だ
Time stops. \"We meet again,\" you say. It's definitely love.
また会えたねと君
\"We meet again,\" you say,
やっぱり恋だ
it's definitely love.
きっと少女漫画じゃ両思い
I'm sure in a shoujo manga it's mutual feelings—
ベタでいいじゃんむしろベタがいいじゃん
cliché is fine, actually cliché is better.
モブ女の私もヒロインなる気ありですなんてね
Even mob-girl me wants to be a heroine, you know!
すぐにくっついちゃえばいい
We should just get together right away,
悲劇はいらないいいねシェイクスピア
no tragedies needed, okay Shakespeare?
やっと会えた王子様
My long-awaited prince,
まずは名前を知ることだよね
first I need to know his name.
ヒロインらしく自然に
Naturally, like a heroine,
バレちまった最悪な奴らに
exposed to the worst guys—
「これじゃだめだ100振られる」って
\"This is no good, you'll get rejected 100%\"
どうすればいいの？
what should I do?!
気持ちなら負けないなんてみんな同じこと思ってて
Everyone thinks the same: \"I won't lose in feelings,\"
気持ちなら負けないなんて
\"I won't lose in feelings,\"
なんてみんな同じこと思ってて
everyone thinks the same.
きっとヒロインなら綺麗で
I'm sure if you're a heroine, you're pretty,
王子様にチヤホヤされるでしょ？
and pampered by princes, right?
秘密の私もお姫様になれるのなんてね
It'd be nice if secret me could become a princess too...
自信ちょっとついたよ
I've gained a little confidence,
当たって砕けたらバカにして笑ってよお願い
if I crash and burn, make fun of me and laugh, please!
行ってきます告白
I'm going off to confess!
「はじめまして」とか何回言ったっけ
How many times have I said \"Nice to meet you\"?
アタシ、ホントは人見知りでさ
To be honest, I'm actually shy.
ドキドキしてるよ 実は今だって
My heart is pounding, even right now.
上手に歌えている? ねえ恐いんだ今でも
Am I singing well? Hey, even now I'm scared.
それでも伝えたい だからきっと頑張れるんだって
Even so, I want to convey my feelings, that's why I know I can do my best.
逃げないんだ
I won't run away.
君に出会って みんな出会って
Meeting you, meeting everyone,
”アタシ”であって良かったよ
I'm so glad I am "me".
何回言ったって足りないよ 声に出して 39
No matter how many times I say it, it's not enough. Say it out loud: 39!
あれ なんかんだアタシの名前みたい(笑)
Huh, it sounds kind of like my name (lol).
今日もありがとう
Thank you for today too.
「はじめまして」とか何回言ったっけ
How many times have I said "Nice to meet you"?
アタシ ホントに嬉しかったんだ
To be honest, I was so happy.
ワクワクしてるよ これからもずっと
I'm so excited, and from now on forever...
走り出せ 前向いて
Run forward, facing ahead,
かじかむ手で 空に描いた
drawing in the sky with numb hands.
君の未来に 祝福の灯火灯そう
Lighting the lamp of blessing on your future.
ワクワクしてるよ
I'm getting so excited!
これからもずっと
And from now on too,
広がっていくんだあ
it will keep expanding.
繋がっていけるんだ
We can connect with each other.
跳ねる音を紡ぐ 描いていく
Spinning leaping sounds, sketching them out,
筆先奏でて 音を追って
playing with brush tips, chasing the sounds.
生まれていく輪の中で 泣きたくなること
Inside the expanding circle, things that make me want to cry
たくさんあったよ でも笑ってばかりだったな
were so many, but I was always just smiling.
ごめんね ありがとう
Sorry, and thank you.
知り合えたよ おかえり
We got to know each other, welcome back.
沈むよ
Enveloping you.
プレゼント 私だけもらってばかりじゃいやだから
If I'm the only one always receiving presents, that wouldn't do,
受け取ってもらえなきゃ困る
so you have to accept this too.
この歌を
This song...
君に出会って みんな出会って 私に出会って よかったよ
Meeting you, meeting everyone, meeting me—I'm so glad.
何回言ったって足りないよ 声に出して サンキュー
No matter how many times I say it, it's not enough. Say it out loud: Thank you!
あれなんだか 私の名前みたい 今日も そして明日だってこの先だって
Oh somehow, it sounds like my name. Today, tomorrow, and forever ahead,
私はずっとそこにいる 何かあったら 気軽に来てよ歌うよ 何度だって
I'll always be right there. If anything happens, come on over, I'll sing for you anytime.
初めてのシステムも相変わらず久しぶりもみんな ありがとう Yeah!
To the first-time system, the usual, and those after a long time—thank you everyone! Yeah!
1回水飲んでいい？
Can I take a sip of water?
ふぅ…水飲ませて
Whew... Let me drink some water.
つぎで、2曲連続、歌わせていただきましたー！
Next, I just sang two songs in a row!
はい！いかがだったでしょうかね？アイドルになったんで、広い育成計画と、そしてみんなにね、ありがとうの気持ちを込めて、サンキューを歌わせていただきましたー！
Yes! How was it? Since I became an idol, with my grand training plan and filling it with gratitude to everyone, I sang "Thank You!"
ありがとうございます！やばい、話さなきゃいけないことがこれからいっぱいあるんですけども
Thank you so much! Oh man, there's so much I have to talk about from now on, but...
っていうことは、みんなに何が来るか分かりますね？そうです、ここからドトールの告知タイムです！イェーイ！
That means you all know what's coming next, right? That's right, from here is the final announcement time! Yay!
ちょっとお付き合いくださいね、お願いしますね。
Please bear with me for a bit, okay?
それではですね、まず、いっぱいあるんですけど、1つ目から！まず風真いろは、今回もグッズが出ます！こちら、ドン！
So first of all, there are lots, but starting with the first one! First, Kazama Iroha merchandise is coming out this time too! Here it is, bam!
さあ、風真いろは活動2周年記念グッズ、発売が決定でござるー！
Now, the release of Kazama Iroha's 2nd Anniversary merchandise has been decided!
いや、本当にね、素晴らしい今回はですね、みんなとね、いろいろ考えた、あの、あの考案会をですね、意見考案会を参考に作らせていただきましたので、ぜひね、1つずつ見ていければと思います。じゃあまず1個目から見ていきましょうか。
Seriously, this time's collection is wonderful. We based it on the opinion planning meetings we had with everyone, so I hope we can check them out one by one. Let's look at the first item!
2層アクリルパネル
[2-Layer Acrylic Panel]
で、は、こちら！こちらです！はい、超ビレ、2層アクリルパネル、なんと新仕様での飾り物は初めて！ということで、もうめちゃめちゃとってもいい感じですね。
And, uh, here! Here it is! Yes, super... a 2-layer acrylic panel. Ornament decorations with a new specification for the first time! So it's super, super nice.
イラストはさいね先生に描いていただきました！めっちゃね、すごいんだよね、このこくん超ビレって風真が言ってるぐらいだから、ちょっと伝わるかわからないけど、超ビレなのマジで。なのでぜひね、みんなのお家に置いていただければなと思います。
The illustration was drawn by Saine-sensei! It's super amazing. Kazama keeps saying "super...", so I don't know if it gets across, but it's seriously super... So I hope everyone will display it in your homes.
かざま隊証明書
[Kazama Corps Certificate]
はい、そして次のグッズがこちら！はい、ついに来ました！かざま隊証明書でござるー！いえーい！大変お待たせいたしました！
Yes, and the next merch is here! Yes, it's finally here! The Kazama Corps Certificate! Yay! Thank you so much for waiting!
実はですね、みんなから多くリクエストをいただいておりました。証明書今回作らせていただきました！表にシリアルナンバーが書いてあって、裏には秘密のメッセージが書いてあるので
Actually, we received a lot of requests from everyone. We had this certificate made! On the front, there's a serial number written, and on the back, a secret message is written, so
ぜひね、みんなの入手してからの楽しみということで、名前を書くところがあるから、みんな名前ちゃんとマジックペンで書いてね！よろしくお願いします。
as something to look forward to after getting it, there's a space to write your name, so everyone please write your name clearly with a magic pen! Thank you.
お手にとって購入して風間隊員にならないか
By getting your hands on this and becoming a Kazama squad member,
というお誘いでございますので ぜひ買って持ち歩いてくださいね！
it's an invitation, so please buy one and carry it around with you!
では次！
Now, next!
はい、ランダム缶バッジ！ということですね、
Yes, random tin badges! That's right,
今回作らせていただきました。全4種からランダムでお1つお届けでござる！
we had these made this time. One random out of four types will be delivered!
通常衣装とお正月衣装と、えーと新規衣装、ぽこべっとの通常服の4種類
The regular outfit, New Year's outfit, new outfit, and Pokobet's regular clothes,
ありますね。
four types in total.
お正月衣装って、実を言うとグッズにするの初めてなんですよ！
To be honest, it's the first time the New Year's outfit has been made into merchandise!
なので、今回のコンプを目指してもいいですし、買った時に何が届くかワクワクドキドキして貰ってもいいので
So you can aim to collect them all, or get excited about what will arrive when you buy them,
ぜひぜひよろしくお願いします！
so please check them out!
イラストはですね、もちびこ先生に描いていただきました！ありがとうございます！
The illustrations were drawn by Mochibiko-sensei! Thank you very much!
そして次！
And next!
はい、最後はショルダーバッグ！
Yes, last is the shoulder bag!
なんてショルダーバッグなの？と聞いたそこなあなた。
You there asking, "Why a shoulder bag?"
そう、こういうアパレル系もあったらいいなっていう意見と、
Well, we had opinions saying it'd be nice to have apparel like this,
なんと今回ですね、こちらのチャックがついてて、前面側がビニールビニールの仕様になってまして、
and amazingly this time, it has a zipper here, and the front side is made of vinyl,
つまりどういうことかといいますと、あの、痛バッグが作れるショルダーバッグになっております！
meaning that it's a shoulder bag that lets you make an ita-bag!
痛バッグが作れます！大賛成たちの中で
You can make an ita-bag! For those of you who think,
「俺、私、痛バッグ作ってみたいけどまだ…」っていう人がいたら
"I'd love to try making an ita-bag, but not yet..."
今回のショルダーバッグ買っていただいて缶バッジや証明書を入れて風間いろは痛バッグを作ってくださいね！
please buy this shoulder bag and put your badges and certificates in it to create your own Kazama Iroha ita-bag!
そして次！
And next!
はい、えーと、記念ボイスのご案内でございます。
Yes, um, here is information about the commemorative voice pack.
えー「きみと見たい世界」ということでですね、今回のライブをモチーフとした、えーコンセプトの、えーボイスとなっております。
Entitled "The World I Want to See with You," it's a voice pack themed around this live concert.
多くは語りません、聞いたものにしか分かりません、今回も一生懸命声帯を吐きながら頑張っております、よろしくお願いいたします！
I won't say too much—you'll only understand if you listen to it! I worked hard on this, so please check it out!
はい次！
Next!
えーと、そしてフルセットがこちらー！こんな感じになっております、豪華でしょ！
Um, and the full set is right here! It looks like this—isn't it gorgeous?
豪華になっております！そして、今回もですね、あるの？という質問がくるかなと思いまして、今回数量限定直筆サインあります！
It is gorgeous! And thinking people might ask "Is there one this time too?", we have a limited-quantity hand-signed version!
はい、箱押しメッセージと、えーと、そして限定ボイスがついてくる数量限定の、えーと、バージョンのフルセットと、あと通常バージョンね、2種類ありますので、
Yes, there are two versions: the limited-quantity full set which comes with a stamped message and limited voice, and the regular version.
この後21時からなんですけど、配信見ながら数量限定買ってください！すいません、お願いします！
It starts at 21:00 shortly, so please watch the stream and grab the limited edition! I'm sorry, please do!
告知をさせていただきます！この後21時10分頃から、
I have an announcement to make! Starting around 21:10 tonight,
えーと、押したらもしかしたら前後するかも知れないけど5分ぐらい、えー風間いろは1曲目のオリジナル曲のいろはすてっぷ！のMVを公開させていただきます！
um, it might shift a little bit by about 5 minutes, but I will be premiering the music video for my first original song, "Iroha Step!"!
こちらですマジで！遅くなってごめんね！遅くなってごめんねみんな！
Here it is for real! I'm sorry I kept you waiting! I'm so sorry, everyone!
お待たせしちゃいました。いろいろ事情がありましてちょっと遅くなってしまったんですけど、この2周年というこのタイミングで、出させていただくことができました。
I made you wait. Due to various circumstances it got a bit late, but I'm so glad I could release it on this 2nd-anniversary timing.
本当にありがとうございます！21時10分から公開予定ですので、よかったらたくさん聞いてください、よろしくお願いします！
Thank you truly from the bottom of my heart! It's scheduled for premiere at 21:10, so please listen to it a lot!
そして、えー最後の告知になります。この流れで告知をするのがあれなんですけども、
And now, for the final announcement. It's a bit unusual to announce it right in this flow,
なんとこの度風間いろは、オリジナル楽曲2曲目！できましたーー！
but Kazama Iroha's second original song... has been completed!
風を仰ぎし麗容な
Gazing at the wind, so graceful and fair,
かっこいいでござるな！なんてイケメンなんだろう！いろはステップと比較するといい意味で
How cool! What a dashing look! Compared to Iroha Step, in a good sense,
誰やお前ってなる感じのオリジナル曲になっておりまして、えー風間の心の中の葛藤を強くなりたいという気持ちを歌詞にしてもらった曲になっております。
it's an original song that makes you go, "Who on earth are you?", capturing Kazama's inner conflicts and her desire to grow stronger into the lyrics.
こちらですね、作編曲Yunosuke様にしていただきました！本当にありがとうございます！こちらの曲はこのあと24時にリリースされるのと、このあとのパートで
This time, the music and arrangement were done by Yunosuke-san! Thank you so much! This song will be released at 24:00 tonight,
初披露させていただきますので、ダンスと合わせて見てください！よろしくお願いします！でもっかい飲み込みます！
and I'll be premiering it in full during the next part, so please check it out along with the dance! Thank you! Let's swallow again!
っていうわけでですね、みなとの今紹介させていただきました風を仰ぎし麗容な、ダンス付きで初披露させていただきます！それでは聞いてください。
So with that, I have just introduced "Gazing at the Wind, So Graceful and Fair," and I will be premiering it with a dance! Please listen.
風を仰ぎし麗容な
A graceful appearance gazing up at the wind
心寄せてほのか歌う
Singing faintly, pouring my heart into it
花の根になりたい
I want to become the roots of the flowers
色づくその前よりしっかりと
Firmly, even before the colors change,
地に立ちたい
I want to stand upon the earth
唇を芽吹かせる
and make my lips sprout buds.
やらずの雨が降ろうと
Even if relentless rain falls,
惰性に時を過すことなく
without letting time pass in complacency,
よろずの声をともせば
if I kindle myriad voices,
憂悶りし日の記憶にできるから
I can make them memories of sorrowful days.
涙曇りいじる風が吹く
A wind blows through the cloudy tears,
咲く花散らなければ愛されないと 光からの葉節に劣なしと比べられようが
even if compared to a sunlit leaf that flowers must scatter to be loved,
舵をかじわるくらい身を切るくらいに凪を打つ
striking a calm so sharp it cuts through the skin like steering a ship,
有り合わせの先で
at the end of what we have on hand.
心寄せてほのか歌う
Singing faintly, pouring my heart into it
遠くしえに遥かしのぶ
Reminiscing far into the distant eternity,
一滴の一滴をたらし続ける
continually dripping a single drop at a time,
秘密の孤独 感情で口上な心でも
even in a lonely heart of secrets and emotional expression,
湧きとかす思考にくる
boiling thoughts melt away.
芽生えこした戴星は 畝の葉を揺らし誘うの道を進む
The stars born anew beckon as they sway the ridge's leaves, advancing along the path.
規則で育むところもなく 自分を見出して無限情にいただく風よ
With no rules to nurture it, discovering myself in infinite emotion, oh wind,
心寄せてほのか歌う
Singing faintly, pouring my heart into it
留まらず罪渡るかの果ては ただ玲瓏ならば面向くがままに
Without stopping, where does sin wander? If it's pure, just face as it leads,
風を仰ぎ赤むけて まだ玲瓏ならば 直たきな姿に追い風は
gazing up at the wind and blushing, if still pure, the tailwind for a straightforward figure—
咲く花散らなければ愛されないと 光からの葉節に劣なしと比べられようが
even if compared to a sunlit leaf that flowers must scatter to be loved,
舵をかじわるくらい 身を切るくらいに凪を打つ
striking a calm so sharp it cuts through the skin like steering a ship,
有り合わせの先で
at the end of what we have on hand.
心寄せてほのか歌う
Singing faintly, pouring my heart into it
遠くしえに遥かしのぶ
Reminiscing far into the distant eternity,
金色の髪が靡く
Golden hair flutters in the wind.
ごめん 憧れてた 追いかけてた いつまでも そうでいたかった 完璧なあなた
I'm sorry, I admired you, chased you, wanting to stay like that forever, my perfect you.
嫌いになった 同じように
I grew to dislike you, even though
愛貰って育ったのに いつからか 差が開いていた
we were raised with the same love, before I knew it, the gap had widened.
やっと当たり前だったって知らなかった
I finally realized it wasn't just a given.
ねぇ メイビー 神様は試練を与えた 強く慣れと
Hey, maybe God gave us trials to make us strong.
ウザい平等なんて嘘つき わかってても でも…
Annoying equality is a lie, I know that, but still...
可愛いとかモテたいとか 諦めないの女の子だし
Wanting to be cute and popular, because I'm a girl who doesn't give up!
生の本音はエグいから
Raw honesty is pretty brutal,
ちゃんと火を通して食べてね
so make sure to cook it through before eating.
リップサービスはズルいかな？
Is lip service a bit unfair?
それとも以心伝心のレシピ
Or is it a telepathic recipe?
みんな～自分疑ってるかい？
Are you all doubting yourselves?
(いえす！)
(Yes!)
嘘の万国博覧会
A world expo of lies.
(いえす！)
(Yes!)
痛みを飼いならして シャー
Taming the pain, hiss!
嫌い だけど 「 スキ 」
I hate it, but "I love you".
不味く て も 「 オイシイ 」
Even if it's bad, it's "delicious".
着ぐる み を 着 て ハグ し て あげる
Wearing a costume, I'll give you a hug.
泣かさ ない よう に 怒ら せ ない よう に
So as not to make you cry or get angry,
丁度 良く 君 と 遊び たい の だ
I just want to play with you nicely.
ネコ カボリーナ
Neko Caborina,
(にゃー)
(Meow!)
猫 かぶり な
playing the cat,
(にゃー)
(Meow!)
ちょっと 臆 病 な 君 が 好 き
I like you, a little cowardly.
ネコ カボリーナ
Neko Caborina,
(にゃー)
(Meow!)
猫 かぶり な
playing the cat,
(にゃー)
(Meow!)
取り繕っ てる ぼく が 好 き ？
Do you like me when I'm putting up a front?
弱 さ を 知っ てる 君 が 好き だ よ
I love you, who know my weakness.
「 想う 」 と 「 言う 」 と で は 大 違い
"Thinking" and "saying" are totally different.
建前 も 用法 と 用量 次第
Pretense depends on dosage and directions.
みんな ～ 自分 疑っ てる かい ？
Are you all doubting yourselves?
( いえす ！ )
(Yes!)
ひとりぼっち の 音楽 隊
A lonely marching band.
( いえす ！ )
(Yes!)
首輪 の 鈴 鳴らし て （ フ ギャー ）
Ringing the bell on my collar, (Whoa!)
災難 だ けど 「 ハッピー 」
It's a disaster, but "happy".
しんどく て も 「 ヘイキ 」
Even if it's tough, I'm "fine".
アベコベ な 夢 を 見せ て あげる
I'll show you a backwards dream.
傷付け ない よう に 、 追い詰め ない よう に
So as not to hurt or corner you,
夜明 け まで 君 と ふざけ あう の だ
I want to fool around with you until dawn.
ネコ カボリーナ
Neko Caborina,
(にゃー)
(Meow!)
猫 かぶり な
playing the cat,
(にゃー)
(Meow!)
爪 を 丸め てる 君 が 好き
I like you, with your claws retracted.
ネコ カボリーナ
Neko Caborina,
(にゃー)
(Meow!)
猫 かぶり な
playing the cat,
(にゃー)
(Meow!)
涙 を 見せ ない ぼく が 好き ？
Do you like me, who never show tears?
痛み を 知っ てる 君 が 好き だ よ
I love you, who know the pain.
君は猫 猫 ファスナー つきの 猫
You are a cat, a cat with a zipper.
君は人 人 ファスナー つきの 人
You are a person, a person with a zipper.
あれはUFO UFO ファスナー つきの UFO
That's a UFO, a UFO with a zipper.
君は猫 猫 ファスナー つきの 猫
You are a cat, a cat with a zipper.
君は人 人 ファスナー つきの 人
You are a person, a person with a zipper.
あれはUFO UFO ファスナー つきの UFO
That's a UFO, a UFO with a zipper.
君は誰？ 誰？ 特別な人
Who are you? Who? A special person.
ネコ カボリーナ
Neko Caborina,
(にゃー)
(Meow!)
猫 かぶり な
playing the cat,
(にゃー)
(Meow!)
ちょっと 臆 病 な 君 が 好 き
I like you, a little cowardly.
君 も ぼく も なじま ない 世界 で
In a world where neither of us fits in,
やっと 見つけ た 居場所 だ から
we finally found a place where we belong.
ネコ カボリーナ
Neko Caborina,
(にゃー)
(Meow!)
猫 かぶり な
playing the cat,
(にゃー)
(Meow!)
取り繕っ てる ぼく が 好 き ？
Do you like me when I'm putting up a front?
君 も ぼく も どうか し てる 世界 で
In this crazy world of ours,
明日 も また 会え たら 良い な
I hope we can meet again tomorrow.
ネコ カボリーナ
Neko Caborina,
猫 かぶり な
playing the cat,
ちょっと臆病な君が好き
I like you, a little cowardly.
ネコ カボリーナ
Neko Caborina,
猫 かぶり な
playing the cat,
取り繕ってるぼくが好き？
Do you like me when I'm putting up a front?
君もぼくもどうかししてる世界で
In this crazy world of ours,
明日もまた会えたら良いな
I hope we can meet again tomorrow.
神様は夢を与えた
God gave us dreams,
壊れるために喧嘩してやる
so let's fight to break them.
最後まで付き合ってもらうよ
You'll stick with me till the very end.
雨はんで傘を閉じた
The rain stopped and I closed my umbrella.
今まで見えてなかった景色
Scenery I couldn't see until now,
透明が反射して世界を照らした
transparency reflected and illuminated the world.
胸踊る可愛いとか持ってたいとか
Heart-pounding, wanting to be cute,
諦めない女の子だし
I'm a girl who won't give up.
元気よく愛想よく
Energetically and amiably,
たまには愚痴って生きていく
sometimes complaining as I live on.
ネコ カボリーナ (にゃー)
Neko Caborina (Meow)
猫 かぶり な (にゃー)
playing the cat (Meow)
ちょっと 臆 病 な 君 が 好 き
I like you, a little cowardly.
ネコ カボリーナ (にゃー)
Neko Caborina (Meow)
猫 かぶり な (にゃー)
playing the cat (Meow)
取り繕っ てる ぼく が 好 き ？
Do you like me when I'm putting up a front?
弱 さ を 知っ てる 君 が 好き だ よ
I love you, who know my weakness.
みなさん、今日は来てくれてありがとうございました！
Everyone, thank you so much for coming today!
最高の2周年ライブになりました！本当にありがとう！
It was the best 2nd-anniversary live! Thank you so much!
バイバーイでござるー！
Bye-bye de gozaru!